Preliminary Guide to the Institute for Management Science and Engineering records, 1948-1987 RG0095
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Institute for Management Science and Engineering records
1948-1987
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
RG0095
17 Linear Feet
Materials in this collection include logistics research, technical papers, conference publications and books. The collection covers the years 1948 to 1987.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
Acquisition data is unknown for this collection.
Historical or Biographical Note
The Institute for Management Science and Engineering was a part of School of Engineering and Applied Science. This institute is no longer fuctioning.
Collection Scope and Content
Materials in this collection include logistics research, technical papers, conference publications and books. The collection covers the years 1948 to 1987.
Formerly ACC #225 and RG 12.11
Other Finding Aids
Detailed finding aid created by Principle Investigator (1956-1987) William H. Marlow can be found here.
Washington (D.C.); Logistics; Publications; Foggy Bottom (Washington, D.C.); George Washington University; George Washington University. Institute for Management Science and Engineering; George Washington University. School of Engineering and Applied Science
- Engineering Research Associates Papers, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Quarterly Administrative Progress Reports: Volume 1, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Quarterly Administrative Progress Reports: Volume 2, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Quarterly Administrative Progress Reports: Volume 3, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Quarterly Administrative Progress Reports: Volume 4, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Logistics Papers: Volume 1, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Logistics Papers: Volume 2, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Logistics Papers: Volume 3, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Minutes of a Working Conference, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Logistics Papers: Volume 4 [1/2], undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Logistics Papers: Volume 4 [2/2], undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Logistics Papers: Volume 5, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Logistics Papers: Volume 6, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Logistics Papers: Volume 7, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Logistics Papers: Volume 8 [1/3], undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Logistics Papers: Volume 8 [2/3], undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Logistics Papers: Volume 8 [3/3] Revised, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Third Annual Logistics Conference, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Abstracts of 4th Annual Logistics Conference, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
- 4th Annual Logistics Conference, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
- 4th Annual Logistics Conference, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Fifth Annual Logistics Conference, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Proceedings of Fifth Annual Logistics Conference, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Logistics Papers: Volume 9, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Logistics Papers: Volume 10 [1/2], undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Logistics Papers: Volume 10 [2/2], undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Logistics Papers: Volume 11, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Logistics Papers: Volume 12, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Logistics Papers: Volume 13 Logistics Papers: Volume 14, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Logistics Papers: Volume 15 [1/2], undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Logistics Papers: Volume 15 [2/2], undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous Technical Memoranda: Volume 1, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Miscellaneous Technical Memoranda: Volume 2, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous Technical Memoranda: Volume 3, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Miscellaneous Technical Memoranda: Volume 4, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous Technical Memoranda: Volume 5, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous Technical Memoranda: Volume 6, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous Technical Memoranda: Volume 7, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous Technical Memoranda: Volume 8, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous Technical Memoranda: Volume 9, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Miscellaneous Technical Memoranda: Volume 10, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous Technical Memoranda: Volume 11, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Miscellaneous Technical Memoranda: Volume 12, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous Technical Memoranda: Volume 13, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous Technical Memoranda: Volume 14, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous Technical Memoranda: Volume 15, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous Technical Memoranda: Volume 16, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous Technical Memoranda: Volume 17, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Miscellaneous Technical Memoranda: Volume 18, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous Technical Memoranda: Volume 19, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Miscellaneous Technical Memoranda: Volume 20, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous Technical Memoranda: Volume 21, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous Technical Memoranda: Volume 22, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous Technical Memoranda: Volume 23, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous Technical Memoranda: Volume 24, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous Working Papers: Volume 1, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Miscellaneous Working Papers: Volume 2, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous Working Papers: Volume 3, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Miscellaneous Working Papers: Volume 4, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous Working Papers: Volume 5, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous Working Papers: Volume 6, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Miscellaneous Technical Papers: Volume 1, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous Technical Papers: Volume 2, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous Technical Papers: Volume 3, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous Technical Papers: Volume 4, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Miscellaneous Technical Papers: Volume 5, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous Technical Papers: Volume 6, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Miscellaneous Technical Papers: Volume 7, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous Technical Papers: Volume 8, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous Technical Papers: Volume 9, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous Technical Papers: Volume 10, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous Technical Papers: Volume 11, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Miscellaneous Technical Papers: Volume 12, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous Technical Papers: Volume 13, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Miscellaneous Technical Papers: Volume 14, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous Technical Papers: Volume 15, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous Technical Papers: Volume 16, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous Technical Papers: Volume 17, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous Technical Papers: Volume 18, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous Technical Papers: Volume 19, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Miscellaneous Technical Papers: Volume 20, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous Technical Papers: Volume 21, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
- PL Technical Memoranda: Volume 1, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
- PL Technical Memoranda: Volume 2, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
- PL Technical Memoranda: Volume 3, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
- PL Technical Memoranda: Volume 4, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
- PL Technical Memoranda: Volume 5, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
- PL Technical Memoranda: Volume 6, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
- PL Technical Memoranda: Volume 7, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
- PL Technical Papers: Volume 1, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
- PL Technical Papers: Volume 2, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
- PL Technical Papers: Volume 3, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
- PL Technical Papers: Volume 4, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
- PL Technical Papers: Volume 5, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
- PL Technical Papers: Volume 6, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
- PL Technical Papers: Volume 7, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Semiannual Status Reports, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
  General note
  #16-32
- Accomplishments, 1965-1981 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Proposed Research, 1969-1975 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Proposed Research, 1976-1982 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Miscellaneous abstracts, Technical Papers, and Technical Memoranda, 1973-1982 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- SPINST P4423.27 and related documents, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Chronological file of serials from office of W. H. Marlow, Principal Investigator and Director of Institute, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
  Correspondence, technical memoranda,, Serial Numbers 70000 - 72232. Note printouts of log books for "Series 70000" and ASCII files therefor on diskettes in Box 17
- Chronological file of serials from office of W. H. Marlow, Principal Investigator and Director of Institute, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
  correspondence, technical memoranda,, Serial Numbers 72233 - 73125. Note printouts of log books for "Series 70000" and ASCII files therefor on diskettes in Box 17. Also included in this box are several steno notebooks which were log books for various "Series" in the institute (some associated materials are on microfilm.) An early organizational plan is also included
- 5 Logistics Papers and Minutes, 1949-1957 (Box 15, Folder 1)
- 2 Tompkins Day Files and papers, 1949-1962 (Box 15, Folder 2)
- 4 Marlow Day Files, 1956-1969 (Box 15, Folder 3)
- 10 LRP Steno Pool Files, 1950-1969 (Box 15, Folder 4)
- 2 Fennell Day Files, 1959-1969 (Box 15, Folder 5)
- 1 Solomon Day Files, 1961-1969 (Box 15, Folder 6)
- 1 Maxcap, Metri, papers, 1963-1965 (Box 15, Folder 7)
- 2 LRP minutes, 1952-1969 (Box 15, Folder 8)
- 2 Working Papers: Volumes 1-5, 1951-1969 (Box 15, Folder 9)
- 7 Technical Memoranda: Volumes 1-23, 1951-1969 (Box 15, Folder 10)
- 3 Technical Memoranda: Computer Lab, 1963-1969 (Box 15, Folder 11)
- 6 Technical Papers: Volumes 1-20, 1951-1969 (Box 15, Folder 12)
- 9 Computer Printouts: intouts Usage Files, 1963-1969 (Box 15, Folder 13)
- 9 Computer Printouts: Allow Lists Grids, 1963-1969 (Box 15, Folder 14)
- 1 Computer Printouts: Miscellaneous, 1963-1969 (Box 15, Folder 15)
- 7 Computer Printouts: Negative Bins and Poissons, 1963-1969 (Box 15, Folder 16)
- Astrachan, Max and Albert S. Cahn. Proceedings of Rand's Demand Prediction Conference, 01/25/1962-01/26/1962 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  RM-3358-PR
- Dyer, George C. Naval Logistics, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  Naval Institute Press
- Eccles, Henry E. Operational Naval Logistics, 1950 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  US Navy Bureau of Personnel
- Eccles, Henry E. Logistics in the National Defense, 1959 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  Stackpole.
- Eccles, Henry E. German translation, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Eccles, Henry E. Xerox of part of Russian translation plus correspondence relating thereto, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Eccles, Henry E. Military Concepts and Philosophy, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  Rutgers.
- Eccles, Henry E. Military Power in a Free Society, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  Naval War College Press.
- Geisler, Murray A., Editor. Logistics, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  North-Holland
- Goldman, Thomas, Editor. Proceedings of Symposium on Military Logistics, 09/16/1973-09/17/1973 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  Washington Operations Research Council
- Marlow, W. H., Editor. Modern Trends in Logistics Research, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  MIT Press
- Thorpe, George Cyrus. Pure Logistics: The Science of War Preparation, 1917 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  Franklin Hudson, Kansas City, Missouri
- US Department of Defense. Publications from Logistics Research Conference, 05/26/1965-05/28/1965 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  Warrenton, Virginia
- Volume of Abstracts, undated (Box 16, Folder 14)
- Volume I: Proceedings, undated (Box 16, Folder 15)
- Volume II: Panel on Logistics Planning Elements, undated (Box 16, Folder 16)
- Volume II: Panel on Procurement Practices, undated (Box 16, Folder 17)
- Volume II: Panel on Government and Industry Development and Production, undated (Box 16, Folder 18)
- Volume II: Panel on Practical Inventory Theory, undated (Box 16, Folder 19)
- Volume II: Panel on Maintenance and Repair Concepts, undated (Box 16, Folder 20)
- Volume II: Panel on Logistics Information Systems, undated (Box 16, Folder 21)
- Volume II: Panel on Cost Effectiveness Models and Evaluation, undated (Box 16, Folder 22)
- Volume II: Panel on Measurement of Logistics Performance Effectiveness, undated (Box 16, Folder 23)
- Volume II: Panel on Logistics Simulation, undated (Box 16, Folder 24)
- US Naval Academy. Naval Operations Analysis, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 25)
- US Naval Academy. Revision of US Naval Academy, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 26)
- US Naval War College. Sound Military Decision, 1942 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  3 copies
- US Naval War College. Register of the papers of Henry E. Eccles, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 28)
  US Naval Historical Collection.
- Naval War College Review, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 29)
  Pages 1-27 devoted to H E Eccles
- Listings of present UARMP001 forms, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Overview of Logistics Archives, undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
  8 pages
- Copies of Tables of Contents for "Volumes", undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
- Bibliography [1/3]: Publications, 1950-1991 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  14 pages
- Bibliography [2/3]: Technical Papers and Other Official Reports, 1950-1984 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  Includes 31 pages with index
- Bibliography [3/3]: Technical Memoranda, Working Papers, and Miscellaneous Serials, 1950-1984 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  Includes 69 pages with index
- Logistics Personnel, 1948-1987 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  13 pages
- Series logbooks: SER 06000, undated (Box 17, Folder 8)
- Series Logbooks: SER 04000, undated (Box 17, Folder 9)
- Series Logbooks: SER 61000, undated (Box 17, Folder 10)
- Series Logbooks: SER 07000, undated (Box 17, Folder 11)
- Series Logbooks: SER 08000, undated (Box 17, Folder 12)
- Series Logbooks: SER 62000, undated (Box 17, Folder 13)
- Series Logbooks: SER 19000, undated (Box 17, Folder 14)
- Series Logbooks: SER 09000, undated (Box 17, Folder 15)
- Series Logbooks: SER 63000, undated (Box 17, Folder 16)
- Series Logbooks: SER 20000, undated (Box 17, Folder 17)
- Series Logbooks: SER 64000, undated (Box 17, Folder 18)
- Series Logbooks: SER 21000, undated (Box 17, Folder 19)
- Series Logbooks: SER 65000, undated (Box 17, Folder 20)
- Series Logbooks: SER 22000, undated (Box 17, Folder 21)
- Series Logbooks: SER 66000, undated (Box 17, Folder 22)
- Series Logbooks: SER 70000, undated (Box 17, Folder 23)
- Series Logbooks: SER 67000, undated (Box 17, Folder 24)
- Series Logbooks: SER 71000, undated (Box 17, Folder 25)
- Series Logbooks: SER 68000, undated (Box 17, Folder 26)
- Series Logbooks: SER 72000, undated (Box 17, Folder 27)
- Series Logbooks: SER 69000, undated (Box 17, Folder 28)
- Series Logbooks: SER 73000, undated (Box 17, Folder 29)
- Series Logbooks: SER 95000, undated (Box 17, Folder 30)
- Disk 1: Directory of LOGISTICS01, undated (Box 17, Folder 31)
  READ ME
- Disk 1: Directory of LOGISTICS01, undated (Box 17, Folder 32)
  ARCHVOL ASC
- Disk 1: Directory of LOGISTICS01, undated (Box 17, Folder 33)
  BIB1 EXP
- Disk 1: Directory of LOGISTICS01, undated (Box 17, Folder 34)
  BIB2 EXP
- Disk 1: Directory of LOGISTICS01, undated (Box 17, Folder 35)
  BIB2-IND ASC
- Disk 1: Directory of LOGISTICS01, undated (Box 17, Folder 36)
  BIB2-IND EXP
- Disk 1: Directory of LOGISTICS01, undated (Box 17, Folder 37)
  BIB3 EXP
- Disk 1: Directory of LOGISTICS01, undated (Box 17, Folder 38)
  BIB3-IND EXP
- Disk 1: Directory of LOGISTICS01, undated (Box 17, Folder 39)
  BIB3-IND ASC
- Disk 1: Directory of LOGISTICS01, undated (Box 17, Folder 40)
  OVERVIEW EXP
- Disk 1: Directory of LOGISTICS01, undated (Box 17, Folder 41)
  PERSLIST EXP
- Disk 1: Directory of LOGISTICS01, undated (Box 17, Folder 42)
  PERSLIST ASC
- Disk 1: Directory of LOGISTICS01, undated (Box 17, Folder 43)
  UARMP001 ASC
- Diskette 2: Directory of LOGISTICS02, undated (Box 17, Folder 44)
- Diskette 2: Directory of LOGISTICS02, undated (Box 17, Folder 45)
  SER04000 EXP
- Diskette 2: Directory of LOGISTICS02, undated (Box 17, Folder 46)
  SER06000 EXP
- Diskette 2: Directory of LOGISTICS02, undated (Box 17, Folder 47)
  SER07000 EXP
- Diskette 2: Directory of LOGISTICS02, undated (Box 17, Folder 48)
  SER08000 EXP
- Diskette 2: Directory of LOGISTICS02, undated (Box 17, Folder 49)
  SER09000 EXP
- Diskette 2: Directory of LOGISTICS02, undated (Box 17, Folder 50)
  SER19000 EXP
- Diskette 2: Directory of LOGISTICS02, undated (Box 17, Folder 51)
  SER20000 EXP
- Diskette 2: Directory of LOGISTICS02, undated (Box 17, Folder 52)
  SER21000 EXP
- Diskette 2: Directory of LOGISTICS02, undated (Box 17, Folder 53)
  SER22000 EXP
- Diskette 2: Directory of LOGISTICS02, undated (Box 17, Folder 54)
  SER61000 EXP
- Diskette 2: Directory of LOGISTICS02, undated (Box 17, Folder 55)
  SER62000 EXP
- Diskette 2: Directory of LOGISTICS02, undated (Box 17, Folder 56)
  SER63000 EXP
- Diskette 2: Directory of LOGISTICS02, undated (Box 17, Folder 57)
  SER64000 EXP
- Diskette 2: Directory of LOGISTICS02, undated (Box 17, Folder 58)
  SER65000 EXP
- Diskette 2: Directory of LOGISTICS02, undated (Box 17, Folder 59)
  SER66000 EXP
- Diskette 2: Directory of LOGISTICS02, undated (Box 17, Folder 60)
  SER67000 EXP
- Diskette 2: Directory of LOGISTICS02, undated (Box 17, Folder 61)
  SER68000 EXP
- Diskette 2: Directory of LOGISTICS02, undated (Box 17, Folder 62)
  SER69000 EXP
- Diskette 2: Directory of LOGISTICS02, undated (Box 17, Folder 63)
  SER70000 EXP
- Diskette 2: Directory of LOGISTICS02, undated (Box 17, Folder 64)
  SER71000 EXP
- Diskette 2: Directory of LOGISTICS02, undated (Box 17, Folder 65)
  SER72000 EXP
- Diskette 2: Directory of LOGISTICS02, undated (Box 17, Folder 66)
  SER73000 EXP
- Diskette 2: Directory of LOGISTICS02, undated (Box 17, Folder 67)
  SER95000 EXP